in adobe illustrator there's a really
在土坯插画师中，有一个真正的
handy tool called the blend tool which
一种称为混合工具的方便工具，它
allows you to make lots of copies of
允许您复制大量副本
objects and blend them together in
对象，并将它们混合在一起
creative ways
创造性的方式
inkscape doesn't have such a tool but it
Inkscape没有这样的工具，但它
does come with a couple of extensions
确实有几个扩展
that when used in tandem can mimic the
当串联使用时，可以模仿
function of illustrator's blend tool in
Illustrator的混合工具在
today's tutorial i'll be showing you how
今天的教程我将向你展示如何
[Music]
[音乐]
so getting us started here in inkscape
所以让我们从Inkscape开始
the first thing we're going to have a
我们要做的第一件事是
look at is the scatter extension which
请看散布扩展，它是
allows you to take a single object and
允许您将单个对象和
repeat it along a path as many times as
在一条小路上重复它
you'd like in order to use this
您想要使用这个吗
extension we're going to need a path to
我们需要一条通向
place our object on so for this
为此，请将我们的对象放在SO上
demonstration i'm going to be creating a
演示我将创建一个
spiral you can create whatever path
螺旋形你可以创建任何路径
you'd like this is just the example i'm
你会喜欢这只是我的例子
going to use for this lesson
将在本课中使用
if you'd like to follow along with what
如果你想跟上什么
i'm doing just go ahead and pause the
我正在做的就是继续，暂停一下
video and input these values up here
在此处录制视频并输入这些值
into the tool settings for the spiral
到螺旋的工具设置中
tool and then we'll be good to get
工具，然后我们就可以得到
started once that's done i'm going to
一旦做完了，我就开始
click and drag on the canvas like that
像这样在画布上单击并拖动
to create my spiral and that right there
来创造我的螺旋线，就在那里
represents the path that my object is
表示对象所在的路径
going to follow
紧随其后
so now i have to actually create the
所以现在我必须实际创建
object for this demonstration i'll just
反对这个演示，我只想
be using a simple circle i'm going to
我要用一个简单的圆圈
grab the circles and ellipses tool click
抓取圆形和椭圆工具，然后单击
and drag on the canvas and then hold
在画布上拖动，然后按住
ctrl to ensure that it's a perfectly
Ctrl以确保它是一个完美的
round circle like that
像这样的圆形
and i'm going to give this a gradient
我要给它一个渐变
just to help
只是为了帮忙
demonstrate this effect a little better
将这种效果演示得更好一点
i'm going to make this a solid fill
我要把这个填得很实
color first of something like pink
首先是粉色之类的颜色
and then i'm going to apply a gradient
然后我要应用一个渐变
so let me grab
所以让我来拿
the fill and stroke menu which is
填充和描边菜单，它是
located up here or you can press ctrl
位于此处，也可以按Ctrl键
shift and f on the keyboard to access it
按键盘上的Shift和f键即可访问它
and up here under the fill tab i'm just
在上面的填充栏下面，我只是
going to click this button over here
点击这里的这个按钮
that says linear gradient and as you can
这表示线性渐变，并尽可能地
see right here we now have a linear
就在这里，我们现在有一个线性的
gradient on this object so this half of
此对象上的渐变，因此这一半
the circle is pink i want to make this
这个圆圈是粉色的，我想做这个。
half a different color so let me click
半个不同的颜色，让我点击
on this handle right here and i'm going
在这个把手上，我要走了
to change this color to something else
将此颜色更改为其他颜色
i'm going to use
我要用
a lighter shade of blue like that
像那样浅一点的蓝色
and now i'm going to take the handles of
现在我要接手的是
this gradient and just move this like
这个渐变，就像这样移动
this i'm going to put this one up here
这个我要把这个放在这里
i'm going to hold ctrl to lock it onto
我要按住Ctrl键来锁定它
the axis so we have a nice vertical
轴，所以我们有一个很好的垂直
gradient going like that
坡度是这样的
now what i'm going to do oh by the way
现在我要做的是哦顺便说一句
to zoom in and out hold ctrl roll up and
要放大和缩小，请按住Ctrl键并向上滚动
down the mouse wheel
向下移动鼠标滚轮
so now what i'm going to do is i'm going
所以现在我要做的是我要去
to grab the selection tool
抓取选择工具的步骤
and now in order to make this object
现在为了让这个物体
follow along this path we have to make
沿着我们必须走的这条路走下去
sure that this object is positioned
确保此对象已放置在
above the path now
现在在小路上方
since we created the path first and then
因为我们先创建了路径，然后
the object second we don't have to worry
第二个我们不用担心的对象
about this this is already positioned
关于这一点，这已经定位了
above the path here but i just needed to
在这里的小路上，但我只需要
point that out in case you're using this
指出这一点，以防你使用这个
extension in other ways and you can't
以其他方式扩展，但您不能
figure out why it works
弄清楚它为什么会起作用
the object always has to be positioned
对象总是必须被放置在
above the path like that okay and you
在这样的小路上，好的，你
can change the positioning over here
可以改变这里的位置
using these up and down
上下使用这些
you can lower objects raise objects see
您可以降低对象，升高对象，请参见
right now the path is above the object
此时，路径位于对象上方
which is no good we want this to be on
这不是好事，我们想让它开着
top
顶部
okay so with that in place let me select
好的，有了这些，让我选择
both of these objects and i'm going to
这两件物品和我要去
go to extensions
转到分机
generate from path
从路径生成
scatter okay so now the the settings i'm
散开，好的，现在我正在设置
going to use here
将在此处使用
as you can see follow path orientation
如您所见，跟随路径方向
check stretch spaces to fit skeleton
选中拉伸间隔以适应骨架
link uh length check
链接呃长度检查
spaces between copies i'm going to start
副本之间的空格我要开始了
off with negative 10
以负10关闭
and then we'll take it from there normal
然后我们会正常地从那里开始
offset we're gonna leave that at zero
偏移量我们将把它保留为零
zero cloned and randomly we're gonna
零克隆和随机我们将
leave everything as it is here
让一切都保持原样
and what i'm gonna do once i have
一旦我有了我要做的事情
negative 10 put in here i'm gonna i'm
把负10放在这里我要我要
gonna enable the live preview
将启用实时预览
and it's going to show you what happens
它将向你展示发生了什么
here it's going to show you the object
在这里，它将向您展示该对象
being repeated along the path
沿着这条路不断重复
now if you notice there's lots of
现在如果你注意到有很多
spacing between these objects we want
这些对象之间的间距是我们需要的
the spacing to be decreased so we can
间距将会减小，这样我们就可以
have more objects so it looks more like
拥有更多的对象，这样它看起来更像
a solid line in order to do that we're
为了做到这一点，我们坚定不移地
going to have to decrease this number
将不得不减少这个数字
here the spaces between copies i'm going
在这里，副本之间的空格，我要去
to start off with negative 15. we
从负15开始。我们
started out with negative 10 i'm going
从负10开始，我要去
to go in increments of 5. so i'm going
以5为增量。所以我要走了
to go down to negative 15 now and see
现在降到负15，看看
how that looks
这看起来是什么样子
okay so that looks a little better now
好的，现在看起来好一点了
the reason why i'm going in increments
我之所以要以递增的方式
of five is because if you go too far too
是因为如果你走得太远
much it's actually going to lock up this
它实际上会把这个锁起来
uh it's gonna lock up the extension and
呃，它会锁定分机，然后
it's not gonna work you'll see here in
这是行不通的，你会在这里看到
just a minute let me try negative 20 now
请稍等，让我试一下负20
okay that's looking a lot better i'm
好的，看起来好多了，我是
going to go a little further just for
我要走得更远只是为了
demonstration purposes here let's try
演示目的在此，让我们尝试一下
negative 25.
负25。
and this is what happens right here you
这就是发生在这里的你
get this error message this means that
收到此错误消息这意味着
you've gone too far for the for your
你做得太过分了，你做不到
object and there's no more like this is
对象，再也没有像这样的了
as much as the extension can do now this
扩展模块现在所能做的就是
morning message is a good thing here
早晨的消息在这里是一件好事
because a few years ago i actually made
因为几年前我实际上做了
a video demonstrating how to use this
演示如何使用此功能的视频
extension in an older version of
旧版本中的扩展
inkscape and once you go too far what it
Inkscape和一旦你走得太远，它
used to do is it used to crash your
以前是不是用来撞毁你的
system and you had to restart everything
系统，您必须重新启动所有内容
now they've added this uh fix in there
现在他们在那里添加了这个呃修复程序
that stops it from crashing so we're
这样它就不会坠毁，所以我们
going to go ahead and click ok and we're
继续，点击OK，我们将
going to go back to 20 and we're going
回到20岁，我们要去
to try 21 instead
而不是尝试21
okay that looks good let's try 22.
好的，看起来不错，让我们试试22。
and that's too far so it looks like 21
这太远了，所以看起来是21
is the max i'm going to set it to 21.
是我要设置为21的最大值。
and once i'm finished i'm going to click
一旦我完成了，我要点击
ok or apply and then close and there you
确定或申请，然后关闭，然后在那里
go it generated that object right there
去吧，它在那里生成了那个对象
kind of like how the blend tool works in
有点像混合工具在中的工作方式
adobe illustrator
Adobe Illustrator
okay now if you zoom in on this you can
好的，现在，如果你放大这个，你可以
see it just consists of lots of tiny
看，它只是由许多微小的
individual circles you may be able to
你也许能够在每个圈子里
see some of the color banding in there
看到里面的一些色带了吗
that's because this is a bunch of
那是因为这是一堆
individual circles okay but if you zoom
单独的圆圈可以，但如果你放大
out
输出
it looks nice and fluid nice and smooth
它看起来很好很流畅很好很光滑
like that so now let's have a look at
就像这样，现在让我们来看看
the other extension in inkscape that
Inkscape中的另一个扩展是
allows you to perform some of the
允许您执行某些
functions that the blend tool does in
混合工具执行的功能
illustrator this would be the
插图画师这将是
interpolate tool so to demonstrate what
插补工具，以便演示
interpolate does let me create a text
Interpolate确实让我创建了一个文本
object i'm going to grab my text tool
对象，我要拿起我的文本工具
i'm going to click on the canvas right
我要右击画布
here and i'm going to type
在这里，我要打字
blend in all caps i'm going to triple
混合所有的大写字母，我要加三倍
click the text to highlight it and i'm
单击文本将其突出显示，然后我将
going to change the font by clicking on
要更改字体，请单击
the text editor up here
上面的文本编辑器
and the font i'm using for this
我用来做这个的字体
demonstration is called league
示威被称为联盟
league gothic which is right there
哥特式联盟，就在那里
click apply and there we go let me get
点击Apply(应用)，然后开始，让我获得
out of this menu because it otherwise
从这份菜单中剔除，否则
slows the system down let me grab the
让系统变慢，让我来拿一下
selection tool now let me
选择工具现在让我
make this larger hold ctrl while i'm
把这个按住Ctrl键放大一点
scaling to ensure that it maintains the
可伸缩以确保它保持
aspect ratio
纵横比
and i'm going to put this copy over here
我要把这本书放在这里
maybe i'll make this a little smaller i
也许我会把这个做小一点
want to make this
想做这个吗？
a different color i want to make this
我想做一个不同颜色的这个
yellow
黄色
and what i want to do is change this
我想要做的是改变这一点
from a text object to an actual path
从文本对象到实际路径
otherwise this is not going to work this
否则这是行不通的
interpolate extension it only works on
插补扩展它仅在其上有效
objects that are paths so to convert
作为要转换的路径的对象
this to a path i'll go to path object to
这是我要转到路径对象的路径
path
路径
and now i need to ungroup it i'll go to
现在我需要解开它，我会去
object
对象
on group
关于群组
and then i'll unify it all together by
然后我会把这一切统一起来
going to path
转到路径
union
友联市
and now i'm going to duplicate this
现在我要复制这个
object by right clicking it going to
对象，方法是右键单击该对象以转到
duplicate
复本
and i'll make this one bigger i'm
我会把这个做大一点，我是
holding ctrl while i'm scaling here to
在我缩放到此处时按住Ctrl键
maintain the aspect ratio and i'll move
保持纵横比，我就移动
this one down here
下面这一张
and i'm going to change this to a
我要把这个改成
different color i'll go with pink
不同的颜色，我要粉色的。
and now i'm going to select both of
现在我要选择这两个
these objects at the same time
这些对象同时出现
go to extensions generate from path and
转到从路径生成的扩展模块，然后
interpolate
插补
now the settings i'll be using here as
现在，我将在这里使用的设置
you can see the exponent is one
你可以看到指数是1
interpolation steps this is the number
插补步数这是一个数字
of copies that will be created between
将在以下时间段之间创建的拷贝数量
these two i'm going to start out with
我将从这两个开始
five and then i'll take it from there
五个，然后我要从那里开始
and these settings as you can see here
您可以在这里看到这些设置
we want to leave these settings as you
我们希望将这些设置保留为您
see on my screen and once you're ready
在我的屏幕上看到，一旦你准备好了
click live preview
点击实时预览
and as you can see it took the two
如你所见，这两个人
objects and created five copies of them
对象并创建了它们的五个副本
based on their properties now as you can
基于它们的属性，您现在可以
see these copies they range in size they
看看这些复制品，它们的大小各不相同
go from large to small as these two
像这两个人一样从大到小
objects did and then the color
物体做了，然后是颜色
transitions as well as you can see there
就像你在那里看到的那样
so if i could actually i could actually
所以如果我真的可以的话我真的可以
increase this from five to something
把这个从五个增加到一些
like 10
大概10个
and then you end up with something like
然后你就会得到这样的结果
that or i could even go as far as 20
否则我甚至可以打到20分
that
那
go a little further 30
再多走30分钟
now it's looking more fluid like that
现在它看起来更流畅了
and unlike the other extension i don't
与另一个分机不同的是，我不
think this one has a break off point
我认为这一次有一个转折点
where it locks up and closes i think you
在那里它锁上并关闭，我想你
could go infinitely with this so that's
可以无限地使用它，所以这就是
40.
40.
here's how 50 looks
下面是50岁的样子
and there you go i think you should get
给你，我想你应该得到
the idea let me bring this back down to
这个想法让我把这件事带回
something a little more reasonable like
一些更合理的东西，比如
10.
10.
click apply
单击应用
and then close
然后关闭
and then once you're finished as you can
然后一旦你尽你所能地完成
see here it created new copies from this
看这里，它从这个创建了新的副本
so your original copies are still there
所以你的原件还在那里
in place you don't need to make
在你不需要做的地方
duplicates you don't need to make backup
不需要备份的副本
copies because this is going to generate
拷贝，因为这将生成
a new copy based on this and if you want
一份基于此的新副本，如果您想
to edit this further you can just go to
要进一步编辑此内容，您可以转到
object on group
组上的对象
and now as you can see this consists of
现在，正如你所看到的，这包括
a bunch of individual objects that were
一堆单独的物体，
generated using that extension
使用该扩展名生成
so i think that should do it for this
所以我认为这应该可以解决这个问题
tutorial that is how you can go about
教程，这就是你可以如何去做
working around a lack of the blend tool
解决缺少混合工具的问题
in inkscape if you found this lesson
在Inkscape中，如果你发现这一课
useful then consider checking out my
有用的，那么可以考虑查看我的
inkscape master class it's a collection
Inkscape大师类，它是一个集合
of over 60 videos where i go over all of
60多个视频中，我浏览了所有
the tools and features in inkscape and i
Inkscape和I中的工具和功能
explain what they are and demonstrate
解释它们是什么并演示它们
how they work kind of like how i did in
它们的工作原理有点像我在
this video we even have a private
这个视频我们甚至有一个私人的
community where you can ask questions
您可以提出问题的社区
and get help from me anytime you want
只要你愿意，随时向我寻求帮助
and best of all there's no monthly
最棒的是没有月刊
membership fees you just pay 17
会费你只需付17
one time and you're in for life i'll
一次，你就被判终身监禁，我会
have some information about that down
我有一些关于这方面的信息
below if you want to check that out as
如果您想要将其查看为
always thanks for watching
永远感谢您的收看
[Music]
[音乐]
you
你